Otaku! Otaku!
Are all of these people Otaku?!
East Hall
Artist and Company
Entrance Ahead
Porta-potties
It's so comforting to know all of
these people are our otaku allies.
Somehow, it feels like coming home.
How are they so relaxed?
Time for Summer Comiket!
Keep rolling luggage
close to your person
These lines are so orderly!
The attendees and staff are trained to do this.
That's why despite the crowds,
everything is neat and organized.
How is everyone okay with
standing in this heat, though?
They're not, but we came prepared.
Warm water bottles! Cold water bottles!
Salt candy! Portable fans!
Salt Candy
And a hat for whoever forgot one!
You're seriously decked out. Thanks.
Senpai, can I have a hat?
What happened to the one you were wearing?
You've heard of guys who
think they can climb Mt. Fuji
with no gear and collapse halfway up,
but otaku know their physical limits all too well.
And don't take it from me,
just look over there.
strap with fan
backpack with airflow spacer
drinking tube
You sure here's just here to buy manga?
Comiket Armor
Wait, I know this guy...
Why, if it isn't milord Okumura!
Hey, great to see you guys!
Ogino-san! Magino-san!
I didn't know you were coming for Day 1!
I'm selling my cosroms on Day 3,
but I couldn't resist the
urge to come see everything!
Did you remember all your gear today?
Keep a close eye on your stuff, girl!
I-I'm good today!
Yeah, there's definitely a story there...
I heard through the grapevine that
the four of you are cosplaying together.
You've created quite the buzz.
Really?
Could you perchance get me
an autograph from Mikarin?
I didn't realize you kept up
with regular pop culture, too...
And, just in time for Comiket,
the last of the Rising Stars were posted yesterday!
Mr. Camera's Cosplay Blog
Shoot, I haven't seen it yet!
You must be better prepared, milord!
You may have countless rivals in the world of cosplay,
and though the Four Heavenly Queens
are among them,
their main target are their passionate fans.
I'd say no matter how hard we try,
we won't be able to attract
any part of their audience.
Our target audience should be the wandering
photographers looking for cute cosplayers!
That would make the other relative
newbies our toughest competition!
That makes sense.
So, who's next on the ranking?
Yes, right!
They're coming to Day 1, too...
Ranking #2 and #3!
Cosplayers and real-life twins Lemon and Lime!
These one-in-a-million twin cosplayers and
their high-quality costumes are the next big thing!
Wait, the next two in the ranking are twins?!
And twins are in particularly high demand right now...
They're cosplaying the twin
maids Shiro and Kuro,
HELLMAIDS Season 2 Confirmed!
characters that are all the rage right now!
And they literally just announced Season 2!
I need to see them!
Stop being otaku! They're our competition!
West Hall attendee line is moving!
Oh! The line is moving!
I-is that going to affect us?
I bet actual twins cosplaying
Shiro and Kuro will draw a huge crowd...
Yeah, word of them is gonna spread like wildfire...
W-we just need Aria's dad to
see our pictures, right?
That's right, but unless he keeps
up with all the cosplay news,
he's not gonna hear about us
unless we're one of the most popular posts.
Plus, Aria can only be here today and tomorrow.
We'll do what we can to draw our own crowds
and get tons of pictures taken and posted online!
Too bad we couldn't get this done before Obon...
Sorry, guys.
It's okay! It's like this every year for Obon.
Yeah, but weren't you gonna go to
Comiket to see that Squadron cosplay group?
Wow, is that right, Sensei?
Not quite. I said I might go...
It's okay.
They're posting pics of all the
cute cosplayers in real time.
Cosplay Changing
Room 2 Hours
If they come across while I'm scrolling,
I'll let you know!
Cosplay Changing
Room 2 Hours
Are all these girls cosplayers?!
So many people...
This is our first time at Comiket, too...
This is crazy...
We're supposed to outshine everyone here?
That means everyone here is competition!
N-no, they're our friends!
Sure, but we want to be number one, right?
Well, yeah, but...
Hey, they can be both!
Athletes are friendly with one another,
but everyone wants to
beat the other teams, yeah?
We can just pretend we're on a sports team!
A sports team?
I know you're otaku,
but you have to know what sports are, right?
H-huh?
It's not here... Oh, no...
Hey!
Do you need a wig cap? Here! I brought extras.
Thank you so much!
Aria's right. Everyone here is our friend...
...but today, we're going to crush them all!
Senpai! Sorry about the wait!
Yes! He's never lost this much blood before!
Wait, that's how you're measuring it?
He's redder than a tomato.
Senpai's blushing!
I've dreamed of getting this reaction out of him!
And you all have your weapons this time!
Yup!
Comiket allows long props,
so I worked hard to get them ready in time!
Wow... I can't believe all four
Squadron members are here.
This is the best Liliel cosplay I've ever seen.
It's perfect!
Senpai, what about me?!
You're the best Miriella I've ever seen!
Same goes for Nokiel and Ariel!
I already feel like we're drawing a lot of attention.
That's because your costumes are so good!
I-it's making me nervous...
Hey, Ririsa?
I know I've never asked this of you before, but...
Do this for me today.
The Ashford Chronicles manga ended
on a hot summer day like today.
Thanks for reading the Ashford Chronicles!
Ashford Chronicles: END
The last chapter?! So no more Liliel?!
I didn't know how I'd keep on living after that.
Liliel saved my life, and now she was gone.
I lived for those Monday magazines.
What was I supposed to do now?
If you're not an otaku,
you might think I'm exaggerating.
But...
I really felt that way.
The Liliel: Side Story manga
rescued me from the pits of despair.
Liliel: Side Story
It's what's kept me alive to this day.
The manga my dad created...
So, please... Do this for me today!
Dazzle everyone with your perfect cosplay,
and show Kisaki-sensei
how much we love him!
We will!
Okay, hands in!
Right!
Wait, what?
Liliel...
L-Liliel...?
Explosion!
...explosion?!
Okay, we have to go, Sensei!
No! I need to admire them more before
they're swarmed by photographers!
There you are, Liliel!
Oh, Kai-sama!
Wait, is that...
...who are you?
Nagomi!
Oh, you're doing Racing Mika!
As an official booth girl, too!
And hey, not recognizing me just
means my cosplay is that good.
I see you're not cosplaying, Mayura...
Though you did doll yourself up.
It's a special occasion.
Today was gonna be the year I crushed you.
Please, you don't need me as a rival anymore.
You've got my apprentice!
We'll see about that.
There are tons of Liliel-tier cosplayers here today.
Just look.
Kuro-chan from Hellmaids!
Everyone's got pigtails today!
Even from this far away,
I can see how good their costume is.
Wait, could that be one of
the twins from the ranking?
Lemon... Or Lime. I can't tell them apart.
Come on, Lime!
Why are you taking so long?!
Sorry, it's really hard doing this by myself...
And I'm missing part of my costume.
What, seriously?! Did you forget it at home?
No, I think you put it in your bag...
E-excuse me, could you help me?
Huh?! Uh, okay!
My partner needs help in the changing room.
Could you bring this to them?
Just this, that's it!
We look the same and are wearing the same outfit!
Huh? Why doesn't she just do it herself?
Of course!
Oh, sorry, I was actually asking the guy behind you.
Me?!
MEN'S CHANGING ROOM
Uh... Lemon sent you to help?
Thank you.
Um...
Huh? Yeah?
Sorry, could you zip me up in the back?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you so much.
Here... If you don't mind.
Why does this feel super inappropriate?!
Thank you so, so much!
As you might've guessed, I'm Lemon...
And I'm Lime.
Thanks for the help today!
Of course! I'm Liliel, by the way!
Oh, that Liliel!
Then they must be Nonoa-chan and Mikarin!
That's so cool!
So, uh...
Sorry you had to deal with this.
I hope you're not grossed out.
I mean... S-some people think guys
who crossdress for cosplay are gross.
What are you talking about?!
You're adorable! Your cosplay is perfect!
You're the living embodiment of Shiro!
You're too sweet.
Senpai, does gender not matter
to you as long as they're 2D?!
Great, now my competition just doubled!
Your costumes are amazing!
The attention to detail is bonkers!
Right?! I got it commissioned,
but I kept bugging them
until they got everything just right!
I made sure they used leather for this part
to match the shine we see in the anime,
and that the patterns were
embroidered instead of just printed on!
I'm so glad you did!
They didn't make their costumes themselves,
It looks so much more accurate!
That's what you get with a professional!
but still want to make sure they're accurate...
No wonder they look so good.
Since we're twins, we always watch
the same anime and like the same stuff.
And whenever we see twins, we get super attached.
We're downright obsessed with Shiro and Kuro!
That's why this is our best cosplay yet!
Okay, we've gotta go.
Let's show 'em why the four of us ranked on that list!
Y-yeah!
See you out there!
All the new cosplayers are so nice.
They're just as talented as Nagomi,
but without any of her drama-mongering.
I'm literally right here.
Still, though...
They're gonna be tough.
Between their passion and attention to detail,
plus the cute twin thing
they've got going for them...
And they're doing one of the
most popular cosplays out there.
They're gonna kill it.
Honestly, they're a bigger threat to me than Liliel.
Even someone as huge as
Nagomi is worried about them...
Is it realistic for us to try and beat everyone here?
W-we still have to try our best, for Aria-chan!
Ririsa-chan, you okay?
Come on, let's go!
If we keep wasting time,
we'll lose out on all the good spots!
Right! Let's head out!
Swimsuit and skimpier cosplays aren't
allowed at the entrance or garden cosplay areas.
That's 'cause normal people not
attending Comiket might see them.
Oh, that makes sense.
We're not showing too much skin,
but Aria-chan's bottoms are kinda toeing the line,
so just to be safe,
we'll go to the rooftop area!
Okay!
Holy...
I knew Comiket was big, but damn.
I didn't realize there'd be this many cosplayers.
I'm used to being the center of attention,
but this is like... Stifling? It's crazy.
Even for you, Mikarin?
Damn, now I'm getting nervous.
Wait...
I thought you've been through this, Nono-pi!
I've been here out of cosplay before...
but being in the middle all
of this is totally nerve-wracking.
Look!
It's Shiro and Kuro from Hellmaids!
Lemon and Lime!
They're so cute!
I've seen tons of Hellmaids today,
but I gotta get pictures of Lemon-Lime!
They're on a whole 'nother level...
I'm kind of embarrassed to be here.
Let's find another place to stand...
We need to find our spot!
Already?! But I'm not mentally prepared yet!
C'mon, be brave!
There's no room for cowards up here!
I can't believe I swore I'd become a top cosplayer...
I made such a fuss about it,
but it's gonna be so
much harder than I thought.
I'm like, freaking out...
Aria-chan?
I should've known.
I assumed cosplay would be easy.
Now I know.
I'm so embarrassed,
I just want to go home.
Nono-pi...
Let's do this, Aria-chan!
Come on! We're waiting on you!
Ririsa... Mikarin...
That's right. I'm not alone.
Coming!
She looks a whole lot like me,
don't you think?
If my dad really is the artist
drawing the Liliel spin-off manga...
And Ariel is his original character...
I want my dad to see me cosplaying her!
It's Liliel-chan!
Wait, Mikarin?! Is that really her?!
Nonoa-chan!
Whoa, that Ariel is super cute!
This group is insane!
We're ready for photos!
Looking amazing, Mikarin!
Nonoa-chan, smile!
This is good, right?
We're starting with a huge crowd.
Please. This is where the real challenge starts.
This is where Summer Comiket comes for you.
Any updates, Mita-kun?
See that Liliel group yet?
You're more excited to see it than our Sensei!
Well, yeah!
I'm the guy putting screentones on her every week!
That basically makes her our baby, too.
See how much we love our Liliel, Sensei?
So, updates!
It's been about two hours since the event started,
but I haven't seen any pictures of them yet.
Over here!
Something's off.
Everyone's taking pictures of our group,
but the crowd isn't getting any bigger.
I thought it might be easier for her, but guess not.
What's going on, Sensei?
I mentioned this before,
but Comiket attendees are always on the move.
Everyone's trying to make the most of their time.
The venue is huge,
Did you get Mikarin?
and one day's not enough to get
Yup! C'mon, who's next?
pictures of everyone and buy stuff, too.
Mikarin's drawn a big crowd,
but those people will leave as
soon as they get their picture.
W-wait, though!
What about them?
Their crowd keeps getting bigger!
They're doing popular characters,
but their quality and level of
fame is basically on our level.
No, Mikarin alone makes us way more famous, right?
So why?
Did you get Nonoa and Liliel?
Y'know, I tried, but I couldn't get
any good pictures, so I gave up.
Yeah, Lemon-Lime's gonna look better.
Mr. Camera knows his stuff.
Good pictures? Wait a sec...
Okumura, milord!
How are your girls faring?
Good, but our crowd isn't getting any bigger.
They seem a bit disorganized.
This is one of the troubles with larger cosplay groups.
The more people there,
the more difficult it is to coordinate
poses and gazes to get a good photo.
T'would seem they're only
performing two or three poses here.
You're right, they keep doing the same poses!
Miss Liliel's strength is her infinite number of poses,
but her groupmates can't match that.
There are so many four-person poses I'd want to do,
if I could just get us to do them!
That's why you're seeing less poses from their group.
That means people will take only
a few photos before finishing.
Mismatched gazes and a mistimed
mid-blink
Blinking
blink can ruin a photo, too.
Looking away
mid-blink
Blinking
Perfect!
Looking away
mid-blink
Blinking
Photographers want to be able to
share their photos with everyone,
and they can't do that if the photo
I can't upload this.
None of mine came out good.
doesn't come out to their liking.
I'll put up the Mikarin solo shot.
Let's head out.
Liliel draws an ever-increasing
crowd with her plethora of poses,
but here, with her group, she can't use
any of her strengths
to their collective advantage.
The twins, however, are highly coordinated,
I keep getting great photos of them!
I waited in line forever. Gonna make this count!
and are exhibiting many different poses.
T-that makes sense.
And to make matters worse,
they're about to deal with the greatest challenge of all...
Water break!
Sorry everyone, we're taking a quick break!
Nono-pi, break time?!
I'll be right back!
Choose your next move carefully.
I feel like my head's melting underneath this wig!
We definitely can't take them off now...
Nonoa, your makeup is smudged.
Sensei...
At Summer Comiket,
breaks like these are a necessity.
But, breaks mean you lose your captive audience.
We can't keep going like this...
The World We Create with Our Friends